let's switch gears and let's talk about
Ron Wayne um yeah I read an article in
LA Times when you guys got started and
initially because you know you were
younger in your 20s the industry may not
take you seriously so you bought
somebody who was Runway experienced I
think he was an
atar and you made him a 10% owner
initially and you were 45 Steve was 45
and uh 12 Days Later Ron comes back and
he sells off his 10% saying I want to
sell it back to you for 8 00 that 10%
today would be worth $22 billion if he
was still there what what what happened
with Ron Wayne what was that story about
I don't remember if 12 days is right but
um Steve came to me at one point and he
said okay we're I finally culet Packard
had turned me down and we're going to
start this company to make these little
$20 PC boards for and sell them for 40
and he came to me and he said look
there's this guy he kind of respected
Ron's thinking Ron wasn't one of these
Arch conservatives reading all the
conservative books of the time you know
today he'd be considered a wacko but um
but it makes him sound very
authoritative and he had so much
experience in companies and having stock
in some companies and getting screwed by
the executives and knowing how these
things work and he attracted Steve Jobs
so Steve said well let's hire we can
hire him and he will he'll do a manual
for us he's good at doing manuals he sat
down to the typewriter and typed out a
um our partnership agreement all the
legal phrases and words and and uh I
mean I don't know how a person knows how
to do that he was incredibly talented he
drew the sketch an etching by hand of
Newton Under The Apple Tree for our
first the cover of our first Apple One
manual and um and he was great I know he
was with us more than 12 days though and
so so Steve's proposed that Ron would
have 10% so if Steve and I disagreed
about something Ron could could resolve
it and I met Ron and was wow so
impressive he knew all these different
things and he referred me to a bunch of
books and when I got home there kind of
trash to me none dare call it treason
and that kind of stuff but um but um I
really respected his ability to think
and and to resolve things the right way
so that was his purpose and then what
happened was we got this order out of
the thin air to build computer boards
with with parts on them and sell them
for $500 each a $50,000 order and like I
said my salary $25,000 this was scary
stuff cuz now we're in big business and
I don't want to make Cula Packard think
I'm you know doing something behind
their back
well what happened was we'd get the
parts on 30 days credit build them in 10
days as I said deliver them to the store
and Ron Wayne figured out that what if
something goes bad and we don't get paid
then who owes the money on the parts
well it turns out that Steve Jobs had
zero bank account you know Z I had zero
bank account no savings account no
nothing none of us had any wealthy
friends so Ron Wayne all of his money
would be at stake so he was taking the
100% of the Financial Risk risk for 10%
of the company and um it was too flaky
and and he sold out he you know he
didn't have a vision there was a big
picture but it was so early with just
the Apple 1 it was hard to see where
Apple would go the Apple 2 really um
changed the story and that came about 3
months later so so it takes a little bit
of I think Ron was with us for for a few
months he was with you for a few months
yeah so what was his reason for quitting
outside of that did he have outside
influence that say these guys may get Su
these guys may be out of business these
guys may have this I never heard a
reason for Ron quitting Steve just told
me he wanted to sell sell out and he
walked away from it I'm so I'm guessing
his reason his reasoning would have been
good and he walked away from it yeah and
very happily and
um so is he an Apple fan I guess that be
a question every time he looks at Apple
that's $22 billion right there I I I
actually I actually talked to him now
and then and he's um a little bit on the
poe side so he's can't always afford
Apple stuff yeah that's what that's
that's actually what it said in the
article yeah it said in the article he
now collects stamps and sells coins to
supplement the social security income
and you know you hear a story like that
you feel bad because you know the
opportunity was so but that's so common
in other Industries as well people hear
a story they they come and they want to
be part of it last minute they get
afraid and they want to walk away from